<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://whaies.dev/">
  <title>whaies.dev rss</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://whaies.dev/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://whaies.dev/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-29T20:40:52Z</updated>
  <id>https://whaies.dev/</id>
  <author>
    <name>whaies</name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Don&#39;t Miss It All.</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/Don&#39;t%20Miss%20It%20All/"/>
    <updated>2023-09-29T20:40:27Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/Don&#39;t%20Miss%20It%20All/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Don&#39;t Miss It All.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, it won&#39;t be like this forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sit upon the precipice of grand emotions, thinking back to the past and ruminating on the present. Back then, we didn&#39;t realize this wouldn&#39;t last forever. Now we know it, and we still can&#39;t do anything about it. I guess the only real difference is the awareness we get to have now. I&#39;m trying to get these thoughts out in a way that makes sense, but it&#39;s not working super well so far. I think my point is that you get to choose to be present and appreciate the now for what it is. Every day may not be noteworthy, but each one has a better chance of sticking if you care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is a good day, and life is good right now. I&#39;m extremely blessed to be in the places I am, around the people I&#39;m privileged to call my family and friends. I want to mark this day down, and the next, and all the ones after that. The worst part of depression is the way it tricks you into believing that life is nothing more than a haze, day after day. I&#39;ve dealt with a bad bout of it this year, despite the first half being some of the best days of my adult life. Time to take the reins back and finish strong. I have a good feeling about it. I might find more to write about this subject, as it feels like there could be more. For now, this is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could miss it all. Please don&#39;t miss it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/748NBl59GV0pfENbadjSxE?si=75f4ba73932a4dcb&quot;&gt;It Won&#39;t Be Like This Forever.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I want to believe.</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/I%20want%20to%20believe/"/>
    <updated>2023-09-22T17:10:10Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/I%20want%20to%20believe/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;I want to believe.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching up and out, all the way to the stars. Grasping, gasping, seeking...wondering what&#39;s out there. All the way beyond, there&#39;s more. I&#39;ve felt very, very close to the ground lately. Depression has a way of fogging up the windows, shrinking the house. Before long, you don&#39;t even realize that you can&#39;t tell which way is up. But all the same...I&#39;ve always been able to tell which way is up. The clouds, the sky, the stars, beyond, calling. There is more, far beyond that which we can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s something about the concept of deep magic in the world, the unseen rules of reality that keep the fabric of things together. While it&#39;s important to stay rooted in reality, I think there&#39;s something deeply valuable to keeping your eyes and ears open to that which can&#39;t be easily explained. A phrase I&#39;ve thought about a lot the past few months is the classic, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;I want to believe,&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; quote that I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; originates with the X Files. I don&#39;t actually know for sure because I&#39;ve never watched it. I&#39;m compelled by the idea of wanting to believe in something you don&#39;t actually think is real. I think that&#39;s how I feel about exploration and the unknown. I want to believe there are new, habitable worlds out there, potentially with alien life. I want to believe there are hidden creatures that live among us, good or bad, in the shadows and in the light. Do I? Not really. But I want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always been drawn to things that give me a sense that there&#39;s more to explore, something to reach for out there. I find it&#39;s harder to chase this as an adult, due to the many priorities that come first. Maybe that&#39;s just an excuse, I&#39;m not sure. Either way, I&#39;m thinking it&#39;s good to keep in mind that we&#39;re not in control of much anyways and life is a nice adventure we get to experience, so we might as well try and keep it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been sick this entire week and I&#39;m starting to get stir crazy, send help and taco bell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and happy Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gratitude.</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/Gratitude/"/>
    <updated>2023-09-15T15:58:29Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/Gratitude/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Gratitude.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that consistent happenings make for a good opportunity to reflect on personal change/growth, especially yearly events that rarely change themselves. A year ago this weekend, I was at one of these annual happenings, feeling pretty hopeless. I was waiting on news, news that I hoped would be good and news that could potentially change a big portion of my life. I hadn&#39;t received &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; news up to this point, but it was more that I had been in a period of waiting for over a month, and I was feeling stuck, at the mercy of greater forces that I couldn&#39;t change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&#39;t get an answer for another 2 months, but it was all worth it. In the end, God&#39;s timing was just right, and I get to reflect back on everything now with some serious gratitude. Gratitude not just for the desired good news, but gratitude for how God took something I felt led to, and used it for His glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trying to find some more interesting, maybe even poetic, words to use to describe how I&#39;m feeling, but maybe that&#39;s not necessary. Mostly, I&#39;m thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/0cXV6AoJBnrnrXK0toJHpB?si=0281d86254c246d9&quot;&gt;Gratitude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All my words fall short&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I got nothing new&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How could I express&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All my gratitude?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dated September 8th, 2023.</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/Dated%20September%208th,%202023/"/>
    <updated>2023-09-11T13:51:44Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/Dated%20September%208th,%202023/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Dated September 8th, 2023.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a bike ride this morning and accidentally crossed over into another dimension for a few minutes. I didn&#39;t mean to, I just wasn&#39;t paying close enough attention and rode right through the portal on my bike. I wasn&#39;t there long, but I knew something was different. Time moved a little slower and it was clear that no one else existed here. It was a cemetery, after all. There was a strange, old building that was better off staying just how it was; doors barred, gates locked, and, presumably, any applicable spells in place. I didn&#39;t stay too long, but I did enjoy the view and the atmosphere for a little while. I made sure to ride back through the same row of trees, and I saw kids walking to school, so I&#39;m pretty sure I made it through back to this lovely little piece of dimensional real estate we call reality. I&#39;ve been thinking about it since, though. I might have to go back, see if there&#39;s anything else worth checking out. It was so quiet. Come to think of it, it still is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m posting this in hopes that in the unfortunate event that I&#39;m still over there, it&#39;ll somehow get through. To keep the record straight, I&#39;m posting this on Friday, September 8th. If it shows up later, well...I hope they find me someday.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>About Rain</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/About%20Rain/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-31T19:42:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/About%20Rain/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;About Rain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s the thing about rain. In one short moment, I was swept back roughly 14 years to a much different time. It was summer, warm, and rain quickly seeped into the pavement of the driveway. I couldn&#39;t help but wonder, lost in the simplicity, quiet, and beauty of this moment. It seemed to last forever. I can&#39;t choose when it rains, I can&#39;t really parse out any individual drops, and I don&#39;t really care why it happens. But that&#39;s the thing about rain; it always makes me pause, breathe deeply, and wonder a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s coming down right now, sprinkling me slightly as I sit on the porch. It&#39;s a calming contrast to the loud busses that are passing by as they head to pick up the lucky kids who just finished an arduous day of education. It&#39;s been an odd day, internally. I haven&#39;t been doing a great job of acknowledging my uncomfortable mental state, so I&#39;ve been a bit off-kilter. I tend to distract myself with &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;, when I really just need a little less. I need something to focus on, something that&#39;ll cut out the clutter. But that&#39;s the thing about rain; despite how much of it there is, it unifies everything it falls onto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gutters fill, streets drain, and sidewalks do their very best to not be too slippery. I haven&#39;t seen any toads yet, but I&#39;m imagining them as they hop around, just happy to be alive. Despite the strong desire, I resist the primal urge to stand under the downpour. I really shouldn&#39;t get myself all soaking, especially not during work hours. I know better, because I&#39;m a responsible adult who has better things to do with my time. But that&#39;s the thing about rain; it always fills me with a sense of adventure and hope for what might be coming next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all is said and done, rain is made for cozy days. With each drip outside your window, you can be thankful for the tea, coffee, or hot cocoa that sounded like the perfect companion to the book you were already reading. Although the wondering and exploring of the world is good and even necessary, it&#39;s as beautiful as it is dangerous, rain. Sometimes it&#39;s not so bad to stay in, stay cozy, and appreciate what home is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s the thing about rain; it reminds me of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Month of No Video Games.</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/The%20Month%20of%20No%20Video%20Games/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-25T14:34:40Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/The%20Month%20of%20No%20Video%20Games/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Month of No Video Games.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took off video games for a month! I&#39;d considered something like this for a few years now, but never had the guts to fully commit. I made a very half hearted attempt back in 2020 that lasted maybe two weeks before I just gave up because I had made all kinds of exceptions that made it worthless. This time I went cold turkey, no exceptions, for the entire month of July. The results were...very useful. I hesitate to say eye opening, because I was already pretty certain I had a slight addiction. That said, I definitely found out I did. I didn&#39;t change the world or anything, but I definitely made some proper progress in some areas that were previously neglected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve mulled over a few different ways to go over what I feel like I learned, but nothing really rose to the surface. It boils down to this: I was addicted to games, and I didn&#39;t realize how bad it really was until I was no longer able to act on that with regularity. If I wasn&#39;t playing games, there&#39;s a good chance I was thinking about when I would be able to next. When I suddenly couldn&#39;t, my free time seemed vast and very freeing. If something you enjoy starts to become a compulsion, you might want to consider why that might be and be curious about changing things up. The first two weeks were tough, but I was also riding the high that came with committing to such a difficult choice, so that made it a lot easier. As I reached the end, I was somewhat over it. I&#39;m still unsure if that&#39;s because I needed to take more time away, or if the compulsion had left, leaving me with a genuine desire to enjoy a hobby. Now that I&#39;m most of the way through August, I&#39;ve noticed a number of times where I&#39;m having all too familiar feelings about games that I was in June, so I might need to change things up yet again. I always tell myself I want things to stay the same, but I thrive on change; life is funny like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notable Gains from a Month of No Games -&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started tearing apart our downstairs bathroom!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIY is hard for me, as my perfectionism starts kicking up dust and avoid problems I&#39;m afraid to make worse. However, I learned how to remove a toilet, vanity, and tear down drywall. I also learned that the previous owners put drywall over plaster and now I have to decide what to tear out. :doge:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started working on new songs for my ambient project, &lt;em&gt;time stops at sunset.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This one feels hard for me at this exact moment, as I&#39;ve been having a hard time finding inspiration and getting back into it for a few weeks now. Music is a tough beast for me, as anxiety and perfectionism &lt;em&gt;really get going&lt;/em&gt; when I sit down to try and write. That and I really don&#39;t know what I&#39;m doing with production. On the bright side, I&#39;ve made really good progress, have a decent vision for the EP, and I&#39;ve already learned a lot about production along the way. I&#39;m excited to keep progressing and sharing about it here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read some more.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing super of note here, but I&#39;ve been reading Lord of the Rings, which is really, really enjoyable. Coming from a place of knowing the movies insanely well makes the books open up the world of Middle Earth in a way that&#39;s new, fresh, and yet, still, familiar in the best way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I scheduled my tattoo, which I got done about a week ago!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/S3sprWcoAOk&quot;&gt;Seagull Orchestra by Aerial Promenade&lt;/a&gt; is an instrumental piece that&#39;s always stuck with me, so when the idea came to me a few months ago it felt like right. I wanted a tattoo that would be obvious, but still simple enough to not kill me. Tattoos really hurt, dude. But I love how it turned out, so, worth. &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/AN18FkI&quot;&gt;See the tat here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: I took off of video games for a month, thrived, realized I need to be challenged more, and did some other cool stuff with my extra free time. I recommended finding something like this for yourself if you&#39;re feeling like you need to mix things up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Childhood Eyes Review</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/Childhood%20Eyes%20Review/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-21T18:18:02Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/Childhood%20Eyes%20Review/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Childhood Eyes Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Yellowcard. I&#39;ve loved Yellowcard since I first heard &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/24IBCzEJlHBI0ioxlSuSPA?si=mDBHNiyyQ2mB5Uge3pYdLg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean Avenue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at 13, when my sister gave me the cd to check out. I listened to that album at every possible chance I had during a camping trip to Warren Dunes in MI and I can still recall those feelings 15 years later. That said, I took their breakup announcement pretty hard in 2016. It never quite felt real that Yellowcard was done, even years later and significant life changes on my end. When they announced the Riot Fest show last year, there seemed to be a glimmer of hope. I wanted to believe that maybe, just maybe, they&#39;d give us new music...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are, halfway through August of 2023 and Yellowcard&#39;s new EP &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is available everywhere. Although I always wanted to believe it was possible, I genuinely never thought I&#39;d see this day. Yellowcard has always been a massive part of my life, so It&#39;s been surreal to process; I&#39;m endlessly grateful for the opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, is the new music any good? Bands coming back isn&#39;t unheard of, especially lately, and the results can be mixed. Time changes people, and bands are just made up of people looking to express themselves through their art. I&#39;ll never begrudge artists for taking risks, trying new things, and creating something they love. But, that means I may not always like it on a personal level, even if I respect what they&#39;re doing. Although I&#39;m biased as a lifelong fan of Yellowcard, I still have my favorite albums and eras. I had both high expectations and concerns due to the reality of how difficult it is to capture the magic of the past while also creating something new that isn&#39;t a rehash for the sake of nostalgia. To be clear, I was never worried the music wouldn&#39;t be good, I just didn&#39;t know if &lt;em&gt;I&#39;d&lt;/em&gt; like it. I&#39;ve changed as a person in the past 7 years, and nothing is guaranteed. I was ready to accept any potential disappointment or disinterest. But, reader...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is some of Yellowcard&#39;s best work. These five songs are fresh, impressive, and somehow pull off the impossible by being something incredible for both lifelong fans and new listeners. I&#39;m not sure they&#39;ve gotten enough credit for what they&#39;ve created in &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is partially why I wanted to spend some time writing about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Album sequencing feels like somewhat of a lost art in the age of streaming and tiktok singles, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is crafted with such intentionality that it&#39;s impossible to miss, especially has a long time listener. Each song is placed with a purpose, as we get a brief lyrical journey through Ryan&#39;s thoughts on the past 7 years paired with an ordering that keeps you riding the ups and downs of each song&#39;s specific pace/energy in a way that feels natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opener, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/0LLNyeqLTbyzLqIgRdryM5?si=9e49df614c8d4892&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Three Minutes More&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, sets the stage by being highly energetic both sonically and lyrically. It&#39;s clear that this is something new. The inclusion of Vic Fuentes from Pierce the Veil is a bold choice, particularly since it&#39;s less of a feature and more a duet situation. I was initially caught off guard by it, with the thought of, &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Really? It&#39;s been 7 years since we&#39;ve heard a Yellowcard song and it&#39;s not just Ryan?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; However, that was the only negative thought I had through the whole experience and my perspective has since shifted. Of the 5 songs, it was the definitive choice for an opener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;It&#39;s different this time, looking up at the sky; three minutes more might just save me this time.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title track, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/2ttWOp5QoqdO6zkIJJ4bFh?si=d5f4ed71c1f74b22&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, immediately harkens back to their 2012 record &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/1URxt8zdzFsihGRAv01cb0?si=C5tt5gNDQUO5its5J0Ctwg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Southern Air&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; a somewhat radio friendly ear worm that&#39;s perfect for a summer anthem. &lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt; is the best example of how the EP pairs the familiar summer sounds of Yellowcard with something new. Upon inspection of the lyrics, this is no surprise. If we can find our childhood eyes, maybe we can put aside our jaded expectations of life and see the world with a new perspective, one that&#39;s built on the lessons learned from the past. As Ryan sings out the outro, you can&#39;t help but wonder if Yellowcard might actually be here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;I am the love you need.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track #3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5DOx0sq87YTYeBLJPpDLLI?si=21227503bc344852&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiding in the Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is already one of my all time favorite Yellowcard songs. Ryan&#39;s gone on record noting that this EP inhabits a similar sonic space to their 2006 record &lt;em&gt;Paper Walls&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5DOx0sq87YTYeBLJPpDLLI?si=21227503bc344852&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiding in the Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the best example of this. Driving guitars lead the way as Ryan shares his new love for life and in turn, for Yellowcard, contrasting who he used to be with who he is now. Something I&#39;ve always appreciated for Ryan&#39;s lyrical style is how effortlessly he intertwines concepts. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5DOx0sq87YTYeBLJPpDLLI?si=21227503bc344852&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiding in the Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is easily interpreted as a song both written to a lover and to the fans of Yellowcard, with neither perspective forcing itself as the &amp;quot;correct&amp;quot; one. There&#39;s a fine line between personal reflection that&#39;s a little &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; personal and the kind that&#39;s accessible enough for any listener to appreciate and relate to, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5DOx0sq87YTYeBLJPpDLLI?si=21227503bc344852&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiding in the Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;You and me for the rest of this life... the future I see.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a short aside, one of Yellowcard&#39;s strongest song writing qualities is window dressing. Rarely is there pointless empty space or moments that leave you feeling like that something is missing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5DOx0sq87YTYeBLJPpDLLI?si=21227503bc344852&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hiding in the Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; could have ended on a final chord, ringing out, but instead we get this short, but very memorable, outro segment with a unique guitar part and a final strong vocal statement. Details like these help songs carve out a unique space within a body of songs, especially one as long and storied as Yellowcard&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intro to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3YzMyn5dtH10yyBASazJoP?si=aab224cdf8b4463c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Honest from the Jump&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is another great example of a memorable production choice. Yellowcard experimented with electronic elements on 2014&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Lift a Sail&lt;/em&gt;, so the bits and pieces scattered through &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3YzMyn5dtH10yyBASazJoP?si=aab224cdf8b4463c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Honest from the Jump&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feel like a loving callback, along with being extremely effective. Any song with lyrics that involve space has my interest, so the opening lines remain my favorite:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;We were just distant stars; Cosmic colliding hearts&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3YzMyn5dtH10yyBASazJoP?si=aab224cdf8b4463c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Honest from the Jump&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is notable, and I&#39;m pretty sure the time signature changes from verse to chorus, although I&#39;m currently feeling too lazy to prove it. I learned after the fact that the chorus is ripped directly from one of Ryan Key&#39;s solo songs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/0KeOGxpwUc8A4MJAN4Z9QZ?si=d3dad24b0f484de5&quot;&gt;Brighton&lt;/a&gt;. This isn&#39;t the first time Yellowcard has re-used a previously written song, and I doubt it&#39;ll be the last. All that said, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3YzMyn5dtH10yyBASazJoP?si=aab224cdf8b4463c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Honest from the Jump&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a bona fide Yellowcard anthem that fits right into the upper tiers of their discography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, but certainly not least, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4jYw7PiQxSW5ezUyfhhjmZ?si=70a8220d6f1242de&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Places We&#39;ll Go&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While directly stated by Ryan as being a rework of a song he wrote in 2015 based around a couple&#39;s love story, it&#39;s the perfect sendoff message for &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The very first line references the current state of Yellowcard, through the eyes of the band:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Twenty years passed, it&#39;s wild how fast; were we ever that young?&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been 20 years since &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/24IBCzEJlHBI0ioxlSuSPA?si=mDBHNiyyQ2mB5Uge3pYdLg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean Avenue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Yellowcard took the world by storm, creating a legacy that&#39;s lasted until now. Ryan goes on, speaking to how he&#39;s changed and wants to share that with the fans and those around him, who still have his heart. As mentioned earlier, the blend of Yellowcard/its fans and a lover is perfectly executed here. On one hand, you have a beautiful love story that speaks to how mistakes can be forgiven, wounds healed, and feelings reignited. On the other, you have the individuals of a band who&#39;ve grown to realize the love of a fan base that&#39;s never waned, despite the many years apart. It hasn&#39;t always been easy, but it&#39;s time for something new and good. On top of that, you have a most classic Yellowcard song that&#39;s taken even further by having the crooning of Chris Carrabba in the harmony vocals. It&#39;s everything I wanted for the last song on this EP, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TL;DR is this: Yellowcard has returned with 5 incredible songs in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an EP that easily fits into the upper echelon of their discography. Each song plays a part in reflecting on the past, present, and future of Yellowcard as it currently stands. Compared to a typical EP, this almost feels like a mini LP in both quality and presentation. If you haven&#39;t listened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Childhood Eyes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; yet, I highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and long live YC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://linktr.ee/yellowcard&quot;&gt;All things Yellowcard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/7g4Iij7EeDIraxCXQRQAQo?si=OgP1mMaTQfGrbP3tJo9NRw&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://music.apple.com/us/album/childhood-eyes-ep/1686908777&quot;&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/pWubKtHzRlQ&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>docks</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/docks/"/>
    <updated>2023-07-08T23:30:19Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/docks/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;docks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a fall morning like this, the eastern seaboard is misty and bright. Many a tall tale has passed through this port, for sailors always find something to blame for their lack of haul. But there is something to be said for the sense of unknown found at the edge of a pier. Hours could pass here with the only sound being the familiar creaking of mired wood and sloshing of waves against the old stones that kept guard on the shore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to get lost in thought, lost in memories. I can&#39;t help myself. I&#39;ve always found it easier to stay lost, especially somewhere I&#39;ve never been. Eventually the sun will go down, lights will dim, and dreams will overtake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaves have already started falling. What once was August and the promise of cooler days will soon give way to even colder, longer nights. It won&#39;t be long now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere, far beyond the horizon, a lighthouse stands resolute.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mid year update</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/mid%20year%20update/"/>
    <updated>2023-07-07T15:31:15Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/mid%20year%20update/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;mid year update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just occured to this morning that the year is half over and I&#39;ve barely used this blog! I&#39;ve been taking a little bit of a head down approach to projects, etc., so I think it&#39;s made me hesitant to talk about anything until I had a solid grip on what I was actually doing. But really, that&#39;s an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Recently I have been...&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Lord of the Rings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading through the whole Bible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imitating film photographer on my dslr via a great set of presets and shooting at 35mm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on a 3-5 song ambient EP for my project &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/6UquNOSvZgtbMeTK6drFR8?si=1VZH0KrCSMmcO0t-KXW-vQ&quot;&gt;time stops at sunset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demoing our downstairs bathroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practicing character pixel art, specifically by making characters for a pathfinder campaign I&#39;m in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drinking chemex coffee again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning how to code at work, although I still feel like I have no idea what I&#39;m doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not playing video games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A few things worth noting...&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to give up video games for the month of July to see what else I can spend time on and enjoy, to great results so far. It&#39;s made me think a lot about how I spend my time and that I was probably a bit of an addict. It&#39;s only been a week, and the results have definitely been a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s my hope to complete the EP over the course of July-August, with an August release date. We&#39;ll see if that happens, but I&#39;m feeling positive! A September release date will be entirely acceptable if it&#39;s because the tracks need more time in the oven. I&#39;m trying to use this experience to learn as much as I can and still create something I&#39;m really, really proud of. If you like ambient music, you can check out the two songs I already have out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/6UquNOSvZgtbMeTK6drFR8?si=1VZH0KrCSMmcO0t-KXW-vQ&quot;&gt;spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bathroom project should be done by the end of the year, but sooner is the goal. There are still some unknowns to be discovered in the demoing process, but I&#39;ve already gained significant confidence in my ability to work on such things, which was very needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pixel art is so sick. I love doing it. It&#39;s up there with photography as a hobby that I got into &amp;quot;later&amp;quot; in life and has been so good for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what I &lt;em&gt;haven&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; been doing much lately? Writing. I might have to buckle down and crank out some more blog posts soon. I&#39;m just bursting with &lt;em&gt;soooo&lt;/em&gt; many great ideas and thoughts the world just &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to hear. More seriously, I think it&#39;s interesting how much writing helps me remember who I am. I&#39;m not really sure how to explain that any more clearly at the moment, so do with it what you will. My cat Mo is currently trying to eat a box, so I&#39;m gonna call it here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Missing home, again.</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/missing%20home/"/>
    <updated>2023-05-04T19:32:28Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/missing%20home/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Missing home, again.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golden haze, dancing across the tops of the grass. These memories are etched into your very being, sewn into the fabric of your soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There comes a point in growing up where you have to face the brevity of the past; it flew by without even bothering to give you a warning before it was gone. At least, that’s how it feels. Unbeknownst to the hurting heart, memories never leave us, and neither do those moments. Caught in time, those evenings wrote themselves into eternity. As the sun draped itself across the fields and into our minds eye, we created something that’ll never be lost. Each second just as precious as the last. Close your eyes, find yourself back home. It’s not far now. Halcyon horizons, beckoning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2023</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/2023/"/>
    <updated>2023-03-22T13:26:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/2023/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;2023&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;February was a bit of a drab month for a few reasons, and March is already almost over. It&#39;s difficult to find inspiration at this time of year, to say the very least. However, 2023 has started off differently in a way I believe is worth noting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t necessarily believe every year needs to be given a title or a theme, as I think many of them develop regardless of my input. That said, I felt that 2023 was deserving of a little more intentionality. Throughout Jan-Feb, patterns emerged and developed into some words that I wrote down on February 9th. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vintage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halcyon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m desiring a tender, reverent perspective towards the immutable. What&#39;s good in life and how do we cling to it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus created this world, and, despite it&#39;s broken state, I believe there is so much good in it. I want to find those things, praise Him for them, and keep a level head by routinely immersing myself into them and what they give back. One of the ways I&#39;m attempting this is by refining the hobbies I&#39;ve had into simpler forms. For example, pixel art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://whaies.dev/images/space2.png&quot; alt=&quot;space pixel art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pixel art is a digital art form that&#39;s &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; had my heart, but I never felt brave enough to try it myself. It&#39;s been both greatly enjoyable and almost edifying, as it&#39;s challenged my drawing skills while also simplifying them. There are only so many ways you can use a pixel at a time, but it&#39;s strangely effective. I find the process very gratifying and grounded. It reminds me of simpler times, old video games, and nostalgic moments. It&#39;s brought me great joy to immerse myself in the various styles, learning what I&#39;m drawn to and how I can craft my own style out of what already works. It&#39;s nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on the list will be film photography. I&#39;ve got the film and a camera that &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; work, but I keep avoiding it because of said camera. But I&#39;ve got some trips coming up next month and the deadline is ticking, so it won&#39;t be long now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole post feels like I&#39;m rambling, so I think I&#39;ll call it for now. I mostly wanted to get back up on the blog post horse, as writing more often is another desire of mine for 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://whaies.dev/images/sunset_and_windmills2l.png&quot; alt=&quot;space pixel art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>sparkle</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/sparkle/"/>
    <updated>2023-01-26T15:19:51Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/sparkle/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;sparkle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet me out in the drift, where time stops as the sun goes down. The light is dancing in your eyes as this moment etches itself onto our souls. Right now, there&#39;s nothing more than you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each breath like a wave that crashes across the skies, reaching out to eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heartbeats that cascade into each other, colliding in sparks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like stars meeting for the first time, nothing will ever be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fleeting words and desperate attempts to measure things beyond. You&#39;ll reach for it forever, but never quite catch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/-J9FuvPmMoI&quot;&gt;sparkle.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mahogany</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/mahongy/"/>
    <updated>2023-01-23T20:28:45Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/mahongy/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;mahogany&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;clunk&lt;/em&gt; another dart finding its mark a little further south west than desired, resulting in an eruption of inebriated groans. why do bars all seem to smell the same? I suppose years of smoking, drinking, and sweating eventually sink into their surroundings, albeit slowly. suspiciously tacky surfaces, obvious regulars, and the constant feeling of &amp;quot;why am I here?&amp;quot; but, I must admit there is something endearing about it. after all, I&#39;m sitting here writing about it while slowly sipping on something overpriced. people pass through, bringing their stories with them, and always leaving a little piece behind. human spaces are strengthened by the history they create, and anywhere that serves decent food and drink will likely steward over a wealth of hearty laughs, stolen glances, &amp;quot;remember that time?&amp;quot;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&#39;s nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>errant</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/errant/"/>
    <updated>2023-01-21T19:45:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/errant/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;errant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i stood on the porch, looking out over the lazy waves, and wondering what would come next. the moons were bright tonight, illuminating the various piers in that familar orange glow. it had already been 7 years since Albiion, but nights like these still brought back memories. it was time for a walk. as i passed sleepy cabins, i became lost in thoughts of starlit coves, golden hours, and days spent searching, hopelessly. the memories blurred together at this point, making it hard to know what was still real. but i knew she was real. if anything from that endless prison was real, it was her. i hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i had reached the end of the street. on a clear night like this, you could make out the Echelon field, shimmering out beyond the gates. for a moment, i thought i saw a shooting star.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Into the Wilds</title>
    <link href="https://whaies.dev/posts/Into%20the%20Wilds/"/>
    <updated>2023-01-19T14:24:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://whaies.dev/posts/Into%20the%20Wilds/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en" type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Into the Wilds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sometimes, it just feels like there are no words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;although I prefer not to hide my hobbies from anyone, gaming is not always viewed positively by others. therefore, i find it worthwhile to only talk about it in settings where it&#39;s going to result in productive conversation. i think this is a fair principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently completed the only DLC for Outer Wilds, known as Echoes of the Eye. I could talk about how deeply Outer Wilds affected me, throwing my hat in the ring with so many others. it is a piece of art that reaches right into the soul and leaves a mark you never knew you were missing. any artistic media that deals with the concept of time tends to do this, as we as finite beings can&#39;t quite wrap our heads around the idea of no longer being beholden to the constant demands of entropy that come with &amp;quot;time.&amp;quot; it&#39;s just not within our scope of understanding at this point. Outer Wilds appreciation is a subject of its own that I&#39;ll only refer back to as relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the story and experience of Echoes is a much smaller scope, naturally, as it serves as an addition to the base story. and it does this so well. because of this, I found the story and its ending to be sweet in a way that easily stands as its own incredible section of the Outer Wilds experience. the prisoner, freed. a friend made at the end of time. choosing to step into the great unknown with only the assurance that you knew who and what you loved in your limited time. knowing that&#39;s enough. holding onto the promise that love matters. what you experienced matters, even when it&#39;s unfairly cut short or painfully, unnaturally lengthened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this sticks with me in a way that i fail to describe. for followers of Jesus, we know what comes next. the great unknown isn&#39;t really unknown. but we were created to recognize and create beauty, and I believe that the beauty we recognize in finality is special and worth dwelling with from time to time. this small piece of reality, one that will end, forces us to contend with loss, pain, and choosing what to recognize as good. love. friendship. connection. it&#39;s no surprise that we hold these so deeply, with a God like ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;although Outer Wilds contains only a sliver of the light and beauty resulting from the fingerprint of God on His people, I believe it does all it can with it. it is a story that wastes no time on the meaingless, but chooses to spend all of its time with all that is irreplaceably human.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>